地下鉄のようですね
It appears we've landed in the subway.
Yeah.
みっちゃんたちは
Where are Mitsu and the guys?
見える範囲にはいねえ
Nowhere to be found.
But right now, we need to do
something about the corporal.
それより　おっさんを何とかしねぇと
地上に出れば　臨時拠点があるでしょう
There should be a temporary base
if we go above ground.
そこまで行けば　治療を受けれます
He can be treated there.
Hey, dumbass!
おい　バカ優　聞こえるか
You there?
お前ら　無事か
Are you guys all right?
当たり前だ
Obviously!
こんなとこでくたばる訳ねぇだろう　バカが
Like hell we'd die in a place like this, shithead.
出れそうか
Can you guys get out?
問題ない
No problem!
Then you go ahead!
じゃあ　皆さんは先に行ってください
私たちはちょっと寄り道するんで
We're going to stop by somewhere.
We'll meet you at the defense line!
防衛地点で合流するぞ
えっ　でも…
Um, but...
Don't be late!
遅れんなよ
まずった　司令塔殺し漏らした
Well, shit.
I couldn't kill the commander.
Oh, deary me.
すごい
何人も一気に殺された
That blow wiped out several troops.
It seems the humans are fighting with their best as well.
人間側も主力出してきたなぁ
Their best?
主力
The vampire extermination unit's elite of the elite:
吸血鬼殲滅部隊の中でも　エリート中のエリート
the Moon Demon Company.
月鬼ノ組ですよ
Well, then...
さて　皆さん
Shall we?
準備はいいですか
下等な人間どもを　皆殺しにしますよ
Let's crush these wretched humans.
Hey, jackasses.
おい　お前ら　人間の血はうまかったか
Did you enjoy your meal?
言っとくが　今のが最後の晩餐だぞ
You better savor it, because that was your Last Supper.
Lend me your strength, Demon Blade Mahiru-no-Yo.
力を寄越せ　鬼刀・真昼ノ夜
行くぞ　お前ら
This is it, guys.
If we stand our ground, this war is as good as ours.
ここを守りきりゃ　俺らの勝ちだ
We will exterminate them.
吸血鬼を…
皆殺しにしろ
Every last one.
I don't want nobody to get killed
I'll come and get you; I am always ready to fight
I'll come and get you, I am always ready to fight
So don't take all of the blame
We were all swept away
Don't take all of the weight
You always do
There will always be something you cannot control
We will overcome
We will overcome. Your salvation has begun
Your salvation has begun
No signs, no lights
Such a mess all over
Don't kill your hopes
You make me realize who I need
I'll be there, hold on
They'll change you somehow
So where are you now?
I'll reach you by dawn
The shadows appear
Illusions are born
The fallen angels you run with don't know
It is our pain that makes us all human after all
Torn old sepia photographs show
Our fragile precious world
Our fragile preious world
Must discard it, respond to the call
Choices and
Consequences
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，尽在 i.kamigami.org 和微博 @诸神字幕组
日听:鱼子酱&paper   翻译:小悠&Cece   校对:夜神&Lucifer   时间轴:阿水   压制:久嘉
Is everyone ready?
みんな行くよ
Yes!
はーい
Mika, Yuu, we're off!
じゃあ　ミカ兄　優兄　行ってくるね
Yeah.
Take care.
いってらっしゃーい
See you later.
行ってきまーす
See you later!
Lunch time! It's lunch time!
配給だ配給だ
Yay, food!
ご飯　ご飯
いっぱいもらうぞ
I'm gonna eat a lot!
Now, now, you'll trip over if you rush.
ほらほら　そんなに急ぐと転んじゃうよ
Hey, Yuu.
優ちゃん
今忙しい
Not now.
Hey, hey, Yuu!
優ちゃん
Will you shut it?
うるさいなぁ　何だよ　ミカ
What do you want, Mika?
If you could escape, what would you want to do, Yuu?
もしさ　ここから逃げることができたら
優ちゃん何がしたい
Huh?
What's there to do?
何馬鹿言ってんの　お前
外はウイルスだらけで　人類滅亡してんだぞ
The virus is everywhere outside,
and the human race is practically extinct.
I'm just saying, if we could escape to the outside with our family,
もしだよ　もし
もし僕らが家族だけで外に逃げ出せたら
吸血鬼のいない世界に行けたら
to a world without vampires...
楽しいと思わない
Doesn't it sound exciting?
俺らだけで
Just us?
Yup, just us family.
うん　家族だけで
Sure, it sounds exciting enough, but...
そりゃ楽しそうだとは思うけど
本当
Really?
I guess.
うん　本当
Looks like my work's cut out for me, then.
じゃあ　ちょっと頑張ろうかなー
What?
ううん　何でもなーい
Nope, it's nothing.
Well, I have some errands to run.
じゃあ　僕ちょっと用があるから
Errands? What are you up to?
用　何だよ　用って
Like I said, it's nothing.
だから　何でもないよー
Weirdo.
変な奴
でも　ミカの言った通りにはならなかった
But his idle daydream never became reality.
The outside world is no paradise either, Mika.
外も楽園じゃなかったよ　ミカ
Shall we go, Yuu?
行きましょう　優さん
伍長のおっさんは
What about the corporal?
ご安心を　一命は取り留めました
I've been told he'll live to see another day.
I see. That's good.
そうか　よかった
それより　グレン中佐から私たちの部隊に命令が出ています
Moreover, Lieutenant Colonel Guren has issued our squad an order.
グレンが来てんのか
Guren's here?
えぇ　各拠点に伝令が飛ばされていました
Yes.
Messages were relayed to each post.
中佐は現在　西新宿五丁目の交差点で
He's at the main intersection
of West Shinjuku's fifth district,
holding off the vampires' main force.
吸血鬼の主力部隊と交戦中
Our backup is immediately required.
至急来いとのことです
主力部隊
Their main force...
じゃあそいつら叩けば　俺たちの勝ちってことだな
So we'll win if we defeat them, right?
I'm sure the vampires think the same:
奴らもそう思ってるでしょうね
defeat the Lieutenant Colonel, and they'll win.
中佐を叩けば自分たちの勝ちだと
急ぎましょう　防衛地点でみっちゃんたちと合流し
Let's hurry and regroup
with the others at the defense line.
Then we'll head to the fifth district.
五丁目に向かいます
I said that's impossible!
だから無理だと言ってるだろ
人員はすべて防衛地点に送れとの指示だ
We have orders to send all men to the defense line.
If they manage to break through,
Shinjuku will be no more!
あそこが突破されれば　新宿は落ちるんだぞ
Our own troops are at breaking point as well!
しかし　こちらの部隊も壊滅寸前なんです
We have the extermination unit there, don't we?
殲滅部隊がいるんだろ
Only three members, all of whom are young kids!
殲滅部隊と言っても　たった三人
それも　年端もいかない子供です
On the other hand, the enemy has a partisan platoon!
対して　敵方の遊撃部隊は一個小隊
あっ　優さん
Yuu!
It's only a matter of time until we're defeated.
壊滅は　時間の問題です
Fine. We'll send our own platoon.
分かった　こちらも小隊を送る　現場はどこ…
What's the—
Excuse me!
ちょっといいか
By "extermination unit," did you mean the Moon Demon Company?
今言ってた殲滅部隊って　月鬼ノ組の奴らか
いや　そこまでは…
Um, I'm not sure.
あんたらは
Who are you guys?
We're from the Moon Demon—
私たちは　月鬼…
The three you mentioned.
三人ってのは　女一人に男二人か
Was it a girl with two other guys?
Y-Yes, that's right.
ああ　そうだが
Where are they fighting?
そいつら　どこで戦ってる
Shinjuku Central Park.
新宿中央公園だが
We'll handle it.
俺たちが行くから　部隊は防衛地点に送れ　いいな
Send the squads to the defense line, got it?
Wait, Yuu!
ちょっと　優さん
冷静になってください
Think properly for a second!
まだみっちゃんたちと決まった訳ではありません
We don't know for certain that it's them.
We mustn't act on brash assumptions.
そんな不確定な情報で動いては駄目です
Backing up Lieutenant Colonel Guren
is our top priority!
最優先は　グレン中佐の援護ですよ
Even he would have trouble
against the enemy's main force.
いくら中佐と言えど　吸血鬼の主力部隊相手では苦戦は目に見えています
Shinjuku's defense line is crumbling.
新宿の防衛ラインはすでに機能していません
今中佐を援護できるのは　私たちだけなんですよ
Right now, we're the only ones who can support him!
ったく　きりがねえな
Shit, they just keep on coming.
私と美十さんで援護します
Mito and I will cover you.
You go after the commander.
グレン様は司令塔を
Sounds like a plan.
んじゃまあ　そうさせてもらうかな
I'm counting on you!
頼んだ
面白くなってきましたねぇ
This is most intriguing.
これで第十三位始祖のクローリー君も間に合ってれば
If only Thirteenth Progenitor Crowley had made it,
things would have started looking up.
さらに面白くなったところですが
Oh, well.
まあいいでしょう　ラクス　レーネ
Lacus, Rene.
Round up the others and fend off the humans,
minus that impetuous monster.
部下をまとめて　猪突猛進の化け物以外を抑えて
Yes, sir.
はっ　お任せください
Leave it to us.
So, Mika.
で　ミカ君
ここは一発
Perhaps I'll finally be able to see you,
Third Progenitor Krul Tepes' favorite, in action.
第三位始祖クルル・ツェペシちゃんお気に入りの君の実力
見せてもらおうかなぁ
You and I will kill that disdainful man.
君と僕であの俺様君を殺す　いいかい
Understood?
I can handle him myself.
一人で十分だ
Ah, most heroic.
さすが
He'll regret ever drawing his blade against me.
僕を挑発したことを　後悔させてやる
Come, my sword.
剣よ
My, how scary indeed.
怖い怖い
近いですよ　優さん
We're close, Yuu!
Yeah.
ありがとな
Thanks.
For coming.
来てくれて
グレン中佐が言ってましたよ
The Lieutenant Colonel did say that we were a family.
私たちは新しい家族だって
今いる家族に命をかけろって
And to put our life on the line for this family.
Dumbass.
バカが
What?
He said that as well, remember?
とも言ってましたけどね
Can't say I do.
覚えてねぇな
見えました　新宿中央公園です
There it is.
Shinjuku Central Park!
与一　後ろだ
Yoichi, behind you!
Damn it!
くそ
馬鹿とちびがいねえだけで　こんなに苦しいもんなのか
Of course everything goes to shit
without the dumbass and the midget.
It's because we can't assemble into a formation.
陣形が組めないからな
Here they come!
来るぞ
Don't write me off yet!
なめるな
Kimizuki, behind you!
君月　後ろだ
Die!
死ね
優くん
Yuu!
Yuu?
優
Eyes on the enemy, Mitsu.
よそ見はだめですよ　みっちゃん
敵の部隊はどこだ
Where are the enemy troops?
もういねえよ
Dead on the ground.
The one you just killed was the last.
今優くんが倒したのが最後だよ
What?
Holy shit, you guys! Nice work!
なんだよお前ら　すげえじゃねえか
お前とは腕が違うんだよ
Not really. I'm just better than you.
So? What are you doing here?
で　こんなとこで何してんだ
What do you mean?
何って　お前らが絶体絶命の超大ピンチって聞いたから
I heard you guys were in knee-deep, so I came to the rescue.
助けに来てやったんだろう
Like we needed it.
頼んでねえよ
Hell, the mission was to regroup at the defense line.
つか　任務は防衛地点での合流だったはずだ
You said that.
お前が言ったんだぞ
んなこと分かってるよ
I know.
分かってるけど
I know, but...
But what?
「けど」なんだ
Don't tell me you thought we'd die that easily.
まさか　俺らがこんなとこで殺されるなんて思ったわけじゃねえだろうな
Have some faith in us, will you?
ちったぁ俺らのこと信用しろよ
Yeah, I got it.
悪かったよ　ごめん
I'm sorry.
If you're sorry, then don't do it again.
分かったんなら　二度とこんな真似するんじゃねえぞ
Let's go.
行くぜ
でももし明日も同じ状況になれば　俺は来るからな
But if the same thing happens tomorrow, I'm coming.
What?
Were you listening to me?
てめぇ話聞いてたか
Don't get me wrong, I trust you guys.
お前たちを信用してないわけじゃない
But I'm still coming.
でも　俺は来る
Tomorrow, the day after,
明日も明後日も　これからずっとだ
and forever.
忘れてたよ　お前が筋金入りの馬鹿だってことを
My bad. I forgot you were a serious case of braindead.
Save your breath, Kimizuki.
何をどんだけ言っても無駄だぞ　君月
You just can't fix stupid.
こいつの馬鹿は治らない
Actually, the more you say it, the more stupid he gets.
いや　言えば言うだけ更に馬鹿になるだけだな
C'mon, guys!
お前らな
Now, now.
まあまあ
Well, then.
さて　皆さん
Since the rain has let up, shall we go?
雨も上がったことですし　そろそろ行きますか
Yeah.
Now that all five of us are here.
五人揃ったしね
Yuu.
優さん
All right, let's do this!
よし　行くぞ　吸血鬼どもを皆殺しにしてやる
I'm gonna slaughter all those damn vampires!
Oh, what do we have here?
なんだてめぇ　強ぇな
You're a vicious one, aren't you?
そう　でも君は強くない
Am I?
I wish I could say the same for you.
爆裂しろ　不動明王呪
Detonate: Fudou Myou-Ou Spell.
今の避けんのかよ　たまんねぇな　おい
Tsk, you can dodge that? Give me a break.
爆発が遅いよ
The explosion was far too slow.
それにそんな古い呪術が吸血鬼に通用するとでも
Besides, did you really expect such
old spellcraft to work against vampires?
さすがミカ君
Never a disappointment, Mika.
圧倒的な力と傲慢さ
Overwhelming power and arrogance.
でもその傲慢さは君の足をすくうよ
But if you don't watch your step,
that arrogance will be your downfall.
手伝おうか
Shall I assist you?
なんだよそれ　どこに僕の負けがある
What are you playing at?
How could I possibly lose?
だから君の足元
Like I said: watch your step.
敵は最初から一対一で戦う気はないよ
They never intended to fight you one-on-one.
バレたぞ　時雨
They've caught on, Shigure.
やれ
Kill them.
Sir.
はい
五士　幻術展開
Goshi, you're up.
もうやってる
Way ahead of you.
チェックメイトだ　吸血鬼
Checkmate, vampire!
はいミカちゃん　一つ貸しね
There we go, Mika.
Now you're in my debt.
Damn, looks like we're in deep shit now.
ヤーベ　予想と段違いだ
あの銀髪の吸血鬼が尋常じゃなく強ぇ
That silver-haired vampire is incredibly strong.
ねえミカ君　あんまり人間をなめないほうがいいよ
Listen, Mika.
Don't underestimate humans.
彼らは強かで欲深くて卑怯だから
They're greedy, cunning, and tenacious.
な～んて　元人間の君に言うのもなんだけどね
Although saying that to a former human feels somewhat odd.
うるさい
Shut up.
さて　じゃそろそろ本気でいこうか
Well, shall we take this seriously now?
二人でやれば
If we both work together—
もう問題ない
I don't need you.
向こうのやり口は分かった
I know what their tactics are.
剣よ　もっと血を吸え
My sword, drink more of my blood.
やっぱり傲慢
See, what did I tell you?
その傲慢さはこの間まで人間だったせいなのかなぁ
Does that arrogance come from your status as someone previously human?
こりゃ薬二錠コースかねぇ
Looks like I'll need a second pill for these guys.
いけません　グレン様
You mustn't, Lieutenant Colonel Guren!
よそ見してていいのかな
And you mustn't look away.
Take your own damn advice.
お前もな
Oh? Not bad at all.
やるじゃん
おやめください　グレン様
Please don't, Lieutenant Colonel Guren.
二錠を飲めば　命を落とす可能性もあります
You could die if you take more than one pill!
飲まなくても死ぬだろ　これ
And if I don't, I'll be dead for sure!
じゃなくても　薬の効果時間内にあいつら始末しないと
Either way, we have to take them out
before the effect wears off.
話は終わった
Are you done talking?
なら行くよ
Because I'm coming for you.
そりゃご丁寧にどうも
Well, aren't you polite?
でももうちょっと待ってくれっかな
Sorry, but could you give us a little more time?
どれくらい
How much more?
ちょっとお薬の時間なんで　20秒だけ静かに待ってくれるとありが…
We need to take our medication,
so if you could shut up for twenty seconds, I'd—
まあ待ってくれねぇよなぁ
Yeah, I thought as much.
おまけにてめぇ　さっきより速ぇじゃねぇか
Not to mention, you're even faster than before.
もう手加減はやめたんだよ
I'm not holding back anymore.
戦場で手加減とか　お子様だなぁ
Holding back on the battlefield?
Very childish, don't you think?
そのお子様に殺されるんだ　お前は
Not when that very same child is about to kill you.
くっそ
Oh, man.
こりゃここで
Looks like it's the end of the line.
Oh?
敵の援軍発見
Enemy backup spotted.
ミカちゃん　早く始末しないとまずいよ
Mika, you'd better wrap things up quickly.
まずい　グレン中佐が
Shit! Lieutenant Colonel Guren!
全員すぐに薬を飲んでください
Everyone, please take a pill!
中佐を救出して　離脱します
We'll rescue the Lieutenant Colonel and retreat!
行くぞ
Let's go!
Yeah!
終わりだ　人間
This is it, human.
クソが
You shitter.
グレン
Guren!
てめえ　グレンに何してんだあ
Get...
Get the fuck away from Guren!
また新手の人間か
Yet another human...
もううっとうし
This is such a chore.
ゆ　優ちゃん
Y-Yuu?
Huh?
馴染めた白　鳥がご隅　鼓動獲たツボミも
najimeta shiro torikago sumi
I used to like the light, my corner of the cage
kodou eta tsubomi mo
I'm a flower bud made flesh
置き去り声　眩めた　記憶の影
okizarigoe kurameta kioku no kage
Blinding memories cry after me
I need your blood
i need your blood
You really love 唱える
you read love tonaeru
You speak of love to me
足掻くRed Light
agaku red light
The red lights dance
嗅ぎ分けた音　音と
kagiwaketa neon to
The neon lamps
こじ開けたReasonが
kojiaketa reason ga
and the madness of the world
ただ平行に並ぶ
tada heikou ni narabu
share a vanishing point
Come on break it down for me!
Come on, break it down for me
come on, break it down for me
A river will flow
a river will flow
KEYがない「欲しい」でも　利害鳴る鈴
My desires remain unfulfilled
key ga nai hoshii demo
rigai naru suzu
A melody of ups and downs
懺悔さえ乾いた　４拍子が　奏でた意図を辿る
rigai naru suzu
zange sae kawaita yonbyoushi ga
Our song follows the sheet of our will,
kanadeta ito wo tadoru
no longer capable of penance
木漏れ日の　赤が　騒ぐ
kanadeta ito wo tadoru
Crimson beams assault my vision
komorebi no aka ga sawagu
次回　終わりのセラフ
Next time, on Seraph of the End:
Childhood
Reunion
"Childhood Reunion."